ticketbud.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy Policy - Ticketbud

## Introduction

Welcome to Ticketbud! Ticketbud is an event management, ticketing and registration SaaS platform for event organizers. Ticketbud’s products, features and offerings are available through mobile applications, webpages, application programming interfaces, and subdomains (the “Services”).

When this Privacy Policy uses the term “Organizer” we mean event creators using the Services to create events for consumers using our Services (a) to consume information about, or attend, events (“Consumers”), or (b) for any other reason. Organizers, Consumers and third parties using our Services are all referred to in these Terms collectively as “Users”, “you” or “your”.

Ticketbud is owned and operated by Ideabud, Inc. (hereinafter, “Ideabud” or “we,” “our,” or “us”). Ideabud, Inc. is a limited liability corporation with its principal place of business at 3300 N Interstate Hwy 35, Austin, TX 78705.

We take the privacy of your Personal Data seriously. Because of that, we have created this Privacy Policy which sets forth our policy with respect to information that can be associated with or which relates to a person and/or could be used to identify a person (“Personal Data”) that is collected from Users on or through the Service. If you are resident of the European Union (“EU”), Ideabud, Inc. is the responsible party with respect to Personal Data collected through the Services.

“Non-Personal Data” as used in this Privacy Policy is any information that does not relate to a person and/or cannot be used to identify a person. When you interact with the Services, we may collect Non-Personal Data. The limitations and requirements in this Privacy Policy on our collection, use, disclosure, transfer and storage/retention of Personal Data do not apply to Non-Personal Data.

## Personal Data That We Collect

When you use or interact with us through the Services, we may collect Personal Data. Sometimes this will be on our own behalf and other times this will be on behalf of an Organizer using our Services to run an event. This is an important distinction for EU data protection law purposes and is explained in more detail below.

### All Users

Information you provide to us: For all Users we collect Personal Data when you voluntarily provide such information to the Services, such as when you register for access to the Services, contact us with inquiries, respond to one of our surveys or browse or use certain parts of the Services. The Personal Data we may collect includes without limitation your name, email address and other information that enables Users to be personally identified.

Information we automatically collect: We also automatically collect certain technical data that is sent to us from the computer, mobile device and/or browser through which you access the Services (“Automatic Data”). Automatic Data, includes without limitation, a unique identifier associated with your access device and/or browser (including, for example, your Internet Protocol (IP) address) characteristics about your access device and/or browser, statistics on your activities on the Services, information about how you came to the Services and data collected through Cookies, Pixel Tags, Local Shared Objects, Web Storage and other similar technologies.

When you register for the Services or otherwise submit Personal Data to us, we may associate other Non-Personal Data (including Non-Personal Data we collect from third parties) with your Personal Data. At such instance, we will treat any such combined data as your Personal Data until such time as it can no longer be associated with you or used to identify you.

### Organizers

As an Organizer we will collect Personal Data from you as described above.

Information we obtain from other sources: We may also collect or receive Personal Data from third party sources, such as third party websites, your bank, our payment processing partners and credit reporting agencies.

### Consumers

As a Consumer we will collect additional Personal Data from you, sometimes for our own purposes and other times on behalf of an Organizer.

Information you provide via Ideabud Properties or Applications: If you register for a paid event, you will provide information which is necessary to associate your identity with your registration. In addition, Organizers can set up event registration pages to collect virtually any information from Consumers in connection with registration for an Organizer’s event listed on the Services. Ideabud does not control an Organizer’s registration process or the Personal Data that they collect. Personal Data collected on behalf of Organizers is provided to the Organizer of the applicable event in accordance with “How We Disclose and Transfer Your Personal Data: Organizers” below.

Information we obtain from other sources: We may also collect or receive Personal Data from third party sources, such as Organizers, other Consumers, social media or other third party integrations, your credit card issuing bank, our payment processing partners or other third parties.

## How We Use Your Personal Data

We collect and use the Personal Data we collect in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. We may use the Personal Data as follows:

### Specific Reason

If you provide Personal Data for a certain purpose, we may use the Personal Data in connection with the purpose for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by e-mail, we will use the Personal Data you provide to answer your question or resolve your problem and will respond to the email address from which the contact came.

### Access and Use

If you provide Personal Data in order to obtain access to or use of the Services or any functionality thereof, we will use your Personal Data to provide you with access to or use of the Services or functionality and to analyze your use of such Services or functionality. For instance, if you supply Personal Data relating to your identity or qualifications to use certain portions of the Services, we will use that information to make a decision as to granting you access to use such Services and to assess your ongoing qualification to use such Services.

### Internal Business Purposes

We may use your Personal Data for internal business purposes, including without limitation, to help us improve the content and functionality of the Services, to better understand our Users, to improve the Services, to protect against, identify or address wrongdoing, to enforce our Terms of Service, to manage your account and provide you with customer service, and to generally manage the Services and our business.

### Ideabud Marketing Communications

Where it is in accordance with your marketing preferences, we may use your Personal Data to contact you in the future for our marketing and advertising purposes, including without limitation, to inform you about services or events we believe might be of interest to you, to develop promotional or marketing materials and provide those materials to you, and to display content and advertising on or off the Services that we believe might be of interest to you. See “Opt Out from Electronic Communications” below on how to opt out of Ideabud Marketing Communications.

### Organizer Emails

We allow Organizers to use our email tools to contact Consumers for their current and past events, so you may receive emails from our system that originate with such Organizers and that we send on their behalf. If you registered for an event on the Services, your email address is available to that Organizer. However, Organizers may also import the email addresses they have from external sources and send communications through the Services to those email addresses, and we will deliver those communications to those email addresses on the Organizer’s behalf. The Organizer and not Ideabud is responsible for sending these emails. See “Opt Out from Electronic Communications” below on how to opt out of Organizer initiated communications.

### Other Purposes

If we intend to use any Personal Data in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time the Personal Data is collected or we will obtain your consent subsequent to such collection but prior to such use.

### Aggregated Personal Data

In an ongoing effort to understand and serve our Users better, we often conduct research on our customer demographics, interests and behavior based on Personal Data and other information that we have collected. This research is typically conducted on an aggregate basis only that does not identify you. Once Personal Data is in an aggregated form, for purposes of this Privacy Policy, it becomes Non-Personal Data.

## How We Disclose And Transfer Your Personal Data

### No Sale

We are not in the business of selling your Personal Data. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. Therefore, we will not sell your Personal Data to third parties, including third party advertisers. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may disclose, transfer or share your Personal Data with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below.

### Business Transfers

As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, Personal Data may be part of the transferred assets. You acknowledge and agree that any successor to or acquirer of Ideabud (or its assets) will continue to have the right to use your Personal Data and other information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### Parent Companies, Subsidiaries and Affiliates

We may also share your Personal Data with our parent companies, subsidiaries and/or affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. Our parent companies, subsidiaries and affiliates will be bound to maintain that Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Agents, Consultants and Service Providers

We may share your Personal Data with our contractors and service providers who process Personal Data on behalf of Ideabud to perform certain business-related functions. These companies include our marketing agencies, database service providers, backup and disaster recovery service providers, email service providers and others. When we engage another company to perform such functions, we may provide them with information, including Personal Data, in connection with their performance of such functions.

### Organizers

When you purchase tickets to, register for or donate to an event through the event page, or through a related fundraising page on the Services, we provide the Personal Data entered on the applicable event or related fundraising page to the Organizers of such event or related fundraising page. For fundraising pages, we may provide your Personal Data both to the Organizer charity of the fundraising page and the Organizer of the event to which the fundraising page is linked. In some instances, an Organizer may appoint a third party, who may or may not be affiliated with the Organizer, to create an event or fundraising page on its behalf (we call these third parties (“Third Party Organizers”). For example, and without limitation, a concert venue (the Organizer, in this case) may allow third party promoters or production companies (the Third Party Organizers) to create events that will be hosted at the Organizer’s venue using its Ideabud account. In that case, we may provide your Personal Data to the Third Party Organizers on behalf of the Organizers. We are not responsible for the actions of these Organizers, or their Third Party Organizers, with respect to your Personal Data. It is important that you review the applicable policies of the Organizers, and if applicable and available, their appointed Third Party Organizers, of an event (and the related fundraising page, if applicable) before providing Personal Data or other information in connection with that event or related fundraising page.

Similarly, if you are a member of an Organizer’s organization within Ideabud, your Personal Data will be available to the Organizer and shared with those Third Party Organizers granted permission by the Organizer to view all members of the Organizer’s organization.

### Facebook and Other Third Party Connections

You can connect your Ideabud account to your accounts on third party services like Facebook, in which case we may collect, use, disclose, transfer and store/retain information relating to your account with such third party services in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For example, if you connect with Facebook, we store your Facebook id, first name, last name, email, location, friends list and profile picture and use them to connect with your Facebook account to provide certain functionality on the Services, like recommending events that your Facebook friends are interested in and sharing the events you are interested in, or attending, with certain groups of people like your Facebook friends.

### Legal Requirements

We may disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law in order to (for example) respond to a subpoena or request from law enforcement, a court or a government agency (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements), or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) comply with a legal obligation, (b) protect or defend our rights, interests or property or that of third parties, (c) prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Services, (d) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Users of the Services or the public, or (e) protect against legal liability.

### How We Store Your Personal Data

We may store Personal Data itself or such information may be stored by third parties to whom we have transferred it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We take what we believe to be reasonable steps to protect the Personal Data collected via the Services from loss, misuse, unauthorized use, access, inadvertent disclosure, alteration and destruction. However, no network, server, database or Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us electronically. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Data.

## How You Can Access, Update, Correct or Delete Your Personal Data

You can request access to some of your Personal Data being stored by us. You can also ask us to correct, update or delete any inaccurate Personal Data that we process about you.

If you are a registered User, you can exercise these rights by logging in and visiting the My Account page. Both registered and unregistered Users may also exercise these rights by contacting us directly by email or at the address specified below.

If a Consumer initiates a data deletion request, Ideabud is authorized to delete or anonymize Personal Data of the requesting Consumer from the Services even if that means removing its availability to the Organizer through the Services. However, if you are a Consumer, you understand that even if Ideabud deletes or anonymizes your Personal Data upon your request or pursuant to this Policy, your Personal Data may still be available in the Organizer’s own databases if transmitted to the Organizer prior to Ideabud receiving or taking action on any deletion or anonymization activity.

We will consider and respond to all requests in accordance with applicable law.

## How You Can Access, Update, Correct or Delete Your Personal Data

You can request access to some of your Personal Data being stored by us. You can also ask us to correct, update or delete any inaccurate Personal Data that we process about you.

If you are a registered User, you can exercise these rights by logging in and visiting the My Account page. Both registered and unregistered Users may also exercise these rights by contacting us directly by email or at the address specified below.

If a Consumer initiates a data deletion request, Ideabud is authorized to delete or anonymize Personal Data of the requesting Consumer from the Services even if that means removing its availability to the Organizer through the Services. However, if you are a Consumer, you understand that even if Ideabud deletes or anonymizes your Personal Data upon your request or pursuant to this Policy, your Personal Data may still be available in the Organizer’s own databases if transmitted to the Organizer prior to Ideabud receiving or taking action on any deletion or anonymization activity.

We will consider and respond to all requests in accordance with applicable law.

## How Long We Retain Your Personal Data

We may retain your Personal Data as long as you are registered to use the Services. You may close your account by contacting us. However, we may retain Personal Data for an additional period as is permitted or required under applicable laws. Even if we delete your Personal Data it may persist on backup or archival media for an additional period of time for legal, tax or regulatory reasons or for legitimate and lawful business purposes.

## Your Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to your Personal Data:

### Limit the Personal Data You Provide

You can browse the Services without providing any Personal Data (other than Automatic Data to the extent it is considered Personal Data under applicable laws) or with limiting the Personal Data you provide. If you choose not to provide any Personal Data or limit the Personal Data you provide, you may not be able to use certain functionality of the Services. For instance, in order to buy tickets as a Consumer, your name and email address will be required by the Organizer.

### Opt Out from Electronic Communications

#### Ideabud Marketing Communications.

Where it is in accordance with your marketing preferences, Ideabud may send you electronic communications marketing or advertising the Services themselves or events on the Services, to the extent you have registered for the Services or purchased a ticket and/or registration to an event listed on the Services. You can also “opt out” of receiving these electronic communications by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any such electronic communication. In addition, you may also manage your email preferences at any time by logging in (or signing up and then logging in), clicking on “Account” and then “Email Preferences.”

#### Organizer Initiated Communications.

Organizers may use our email tools to send electronic communications to those on their email subscription lists, including Consumers who have registered for their events on the Services in the past. Although these electronic communications are sent through our system, Ideabud does not determine the content or the recipients of these electronic communications. Organizers are required to use our email tools only in accordance with all applicable laws. Ideabud provides an “Unsubscribe” link on each of these emails, which allows recipients to “opt out” of electronic communications from the particular Organizer.

#### Social Notifications.

If you connect your Facebook account or sign up for other social media integrations whose product features include social notifications (i.e., updates on what your friends are doing on the Services), you will receive these social notifications. You can manage these social notifications by toggling your social settings to private or disconnecting such integration.

#### Transactional or Responsive Communications.

Certain electronic communications from Ideabud are responsive to your requests. For instance, if you are a Consumer, we must email you your ticket or registration on behalf of the Organizer when you purchase such ticket or registration. As a further example, if you email our customer support department, we will return your email. Notwithstanding any unsubscribe election that you have made, you will still receive these transactional or responsive emails. You can stop receiving these types of emails only by contacting us. By electing to stop receiving all electronic communications from us or through our system you will no longer receive any updates on events you have created (including pay-out issues) or on events you are registered to attend (including emails with your tickets). We do not recommend that you do this unless you plan to no longer use the Services, are not currently registered for an event, are not currently organizing an event and will have no need to receive further communications from us or through our system.

#### Retention.

It may take up to forty-eight (48) hours for us to process an unsubscribe request. Even after you opt out of all electronic communications, we will retain your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy, however, we will no longer use it to contact you. However, Organizers who have received your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy may still use that Personal Data to contact you in accordance with their own privacy policies, but they may not use our system to do so.

### Do Not Track

We currently do not participate in any “Do Not Track” frameworks that would allow us to respond to signals or other mechanisms from you regarding the collection of your Personal Data.

## Exclusions

### Personal Data Provided to Others.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Personal Data that you provide to another User or visitor through the Services or through any other means, including to Organizers on event pages or information posted by you to any public areas of the Services.

## Links to Other Sites

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Services. The Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us (the “Third Party Sites”). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. Please note that once you leave the Ideabud website and link to the Third Party Site you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies.

## Children Under the Age of 13

Ideabud does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13, or knowingly allow such persons to register on its website. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register or to send any information about yourself to us. No one under age 13 may provide or post any personal information on the Ideabud website. In the event that we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will promptly delete that information.

## Rights of California Residents

Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information regarding the types of personal information the business shares with third parties for direct marketing purposes by such third party, and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. To see a copy of the information disclosure provided by Ideabud pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact Ideabud using one of the methods described in this Privacy Policy. You and Ideabud may have other rights and obligations under the various laws governing privacy and personal information.

## International Privacy Laws

If you are visiting the Services from outside the United States, please be aware that you are sending information (including Personal Data) to the United States where our servers are located. That information may then be transferred within the United States or back out of the United States to other countries outside of your country of residence, depending on the type of information and how it is stored by us. These countries (including the United States) may not necessarily have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in your country of residence; however, our collection, storage and use of your Personal Data will at all times continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy.

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

The Services and our business may change from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for us to make changes to this Privacy Policy. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. Unless otherwise agreed by a user, we will use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected.

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time (collectively, “Modifications”). Modifications to this Privacy Policy will be posted to the Site with a change to the “Updated” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. In certain circumstances Ideabud may, but need not, provide you with additional notice of such Modifications, such as via email or with in-Service notifications. Modifications will be effective thirty (30) days following the “Updated” date or such other date as communicated in any other notice to you.

Please review this policy periodically, and especially before you provide any Personal Data. This Privacy Policy was updated on the date indicated above. Your continued use of the Services following the effectiveness of any Modifications to this Privacy Policy constitutes acceptance of those Modifications. If any Modification to this Privacy Policy is not acceptable to you, you should cease accessing, browsing and otherwise using the Services.

## Dispute Resolution

If you have a question or complaint about Ideabud’s privacy practices you should write to us at:

Ideabud, LLC., Attn: Privacy Officer, 3300 N Interstate Hwy 35, Austin, TX 78705, or by email at cs@ticketbud.com. We will take reasonable steps to work with you to attempt to resolve your complaint.

Residents of the EEA who believe that their information has not been processed in compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles may raise their complaints in a number of ways. For further information, please see our Privacy Shield Notice.

## Residents of the European Union Only

### The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

In May 2018, a new data privacy law known as the EU General Data Protection Regulation (or the “GDPR”) became effective. The GDPR requires Ideabud and Organizers using the Service to provide Users with more information about the processing of their Personal Data.

Here is what you need to know:

### Legal Grounds for Processing Your Personal Data

The GDPR requires us to tell you about the legal ground we’re relying on to process any Personal Data about you. The legal grounds for us processing your Personal Data for the purposes set out in Section 4 above will typically be because:

  * you provided your consent;
  * it is necessary for our contractual relationship;
  * the processing is necessary for us to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations;
  * and/or the processing is in our legitimate interest as an event organizing and ticketing platform (for example, to protect the security and integrity of our systems and to provide you with customer service, etc.).

### Transfers of Personal Data

As Ideabud is a global company, we may need to transfer your Personal Data outside of the member state from which it was originally provided. This may be intra-group or to third parties that we work with who may be located in jurisdictions outside the EU which have no data protection laws or laws that are less strict compared with those in Europe. Whenever we transfer Personal Data outside of the EU, we will do so only upon your informed and express consent.

We retain your Personal Data for as long as necessary to provide you with our Services, or for other important purposes such as complying with legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our agreements.

If you have an account with us, we will typically retain your Personal Data for a period of 90 days after you have requested that your account is closed or if it’s been inactive for 7 years.

### Your Rights

Data protection law provides you with rights in respect of Personal Data that we hold about you, including the right to request a copy of the Personal Data, request that we rectify, restrict or delete your Personal Data, object to profiling and unsubscribe from marketing communications.

For the most part, you can you can exercise these rights by logging in and visiting the My Account page or changing the “cookie settings” in your browser. If you can’t find what you’re looking for in the My Account page, please contact us using the contact information set out above. Please note that requests to exercise data protection rights will be assessed by us on a case-by-case basis. There may be circumstances where we are not legally required to comply with your request because of the laws in your jurisdiction or because of exemptions provided for in data protection legislation.

If you have a complaint about how we handle your Personal Data, please get in touch with us to explain. If you are not happy with how we have attempted to resolve your complaint, you may contact the relevant data protection authority.

### Ideabud as a Data Controller and a Data Processor

EU data protection law makes a distinction between organizations that process Personal Data for their own purposes (known as “data controllers”) and organizations that process personal data on behalf of other organizations (known as “data processors”). If you have a question or complaint about how your Personal Data is handled, these should always be directed to the relevant data controller since they are the ones with primary responsibility for your Personal Data.

Ideabud may act as either a data controller or a data processor in respect of your Personal Data, depending on the circumstances.

For example, if you create an account with us to organize your events, Ideabud will be a data controller in respect of the Personal Data that you provide as part of your account. We will also be a data controller of the Personal Data that we have obtained about the use of the Applications or Ideabud Properties, which could relate to Organizers or Consumers. We use this to conduct research and analysis to help better understand and serve Users of the Services as well as to improve our platform and provide you with more targeted recommendations about events we think may be of interest to you.

However, if you register for an event as a Consumer, we will process your Personal Data to help administer that event on behalf of the Organizer (for example, sending confirmation, promotional and feedback emails, processing payments, etc.) and to help the Organizer target, and understand the success of, their event and event planning (for example, providing event reports, using analytics to gain insights into the effectiveness of various sales channels, etc.). In these circumstances, Ideabud merely provides the “tools” for Organizers; Ideabud does not decide what Personal Data to request on registration forms, nor is it responsible for the continued accuracy any Personal Data provided. Any questions that you may have relating to your Personal Data and your rights under data protection law should therefore be directed to the Organizer as the data controller, not to Ideabud.

## PCI Compliance

All third party payment processors used by Ideabud are fully PCI-DSS 3.0 compliant. This means that all credit card information is processed in a completely safe environment.

To learn more about PCI Compliance and all it entails, you can find more information and documentation on PCI Compliance Standards

## Additional Terms and Conditions

Visitors to this website may be required to agree to written or electronic agreements, including license agreements, terms of use, and other terms and conditions, as a condition of visiting the website or receiving products, services, and other information from Ideabud. In the event of any conflict with such other terms and conditions and this Privacy Policy, such other terms and conditions shall prevail.
